spectrumhealth.org 2012-12-24

# Website Privacy Policy Grand Rapids, Michigan (MI) - Spectrum Health

**SPECTRUMHEALTH.ORG PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy sets forth the guidelines Spectrum Health ("Spectrum," "us" or "we") uses for protecting the information you ("User" or "you") provide to us during visits to [www.spectrumhealth.org](http://www.spectrum-health.org/) (this "Site" or our "Site"). We are the sole owners of the information collected on this Site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement.

When you visit [www.spectrumhealth.org](http://www.spectrum-health.org/), you may provide us with different types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and Web site use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse this Site.

We receive and store any information you enter on our Site or give us in any other way. It is completely optional for you to participate.

For example, we request information from you when you:  
(1) Submit a request to send a Patient E-mail;  
(2) Provide feed back from an online survey;  
(3) Submit a resume with us;  
(4) Submit an application for a job opening; and/or  
(5) Make a donation to the Spectrum Health Foundation or Helen DeVos Children's Hospital Foundation.

In the instances above, we may ask for your name, e-mail address, billing address, home address and credit card information, as well as other similar personal information that is needed to make a donation and to register, subscribe, or request several of the services we offer.

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you visit our Site through the use of "cookies." A "cookie" is an element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your system and is used to provide you with tailored information from a Web site. In most instances, you can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you a chance to decide whether to accept it. We use cookies information to analyze how frequently areas of the Site are being viewed, for automatic user recognition, and to improve your overall on-line experience with us.

If you choose to correspond further with us through e-mail, we reserve the right to retain the content of your e-mail messages together with your e-mail addresses and our responses.

We will not trade, rent or sell your personal information. We use the personal information we collect for the purposes of administering our business activities, providing patient and guest services, and making products and services available to our patients and guests. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Site, new services, and new information we think you might find valuable. Users who do not wish to receive those mailings (whether e-mail or paper mail) or who believe they are receiving those mailings by mistake can contact us by e-mail and request removal from the mailing list at the following e-mail address: [ContactUs@spectrumhealth.org](mailto:ContactUs@spectrum-health.org).

From time to time we may share the information we collect with agents, contractors or affiliates of ours for the purpose of providing services to us. We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. We use an outside credit card processing company to bill users for donations and services. When you sign up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services.

We reserve the right to release personal and account information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law, other agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Spectrum, our Users or others.

We provide you access to your personal information. You may update, correct or add to your personal information by e-mail request at the following e-mail address: [ContactUs@spectrumhealth.org](mailto:ContactUs@spectrum-health.org).

We may provide online bulletin boards, forums, and/or chat rooms for users who visit our Site. Be advised that any postings will not be protected or confidential.

Please be aware that other Web sites which may be accessed through our Site, may collect personally identifiable information about you. These links are provided as a convenience to you and the inclusion of the link does not imply Spectrum's endorsement of any other company, its Web site, its privacy practices or the products and services it sells. The information practices of those third-party Web sites are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy any time from time to time.

By using this Site, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of this Site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

If you feel we are not abiding by this Privacy Policy, please contact us by e-mail at the following e-mail address: [ContactUs@spectrumhealth.org](mailto:ContactUs@spectrum-health.org). If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please contact us by e-mail at the same address.
